<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Body Building &amp; Fitness Trainer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navigation">NavigationActivity</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="absworkout_1">

        <![CDATA[

        <!--Dubmbell Side Bends-->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Stand up straight while holding a dumbbell in your hands (palms facing the torso). Your feet should be shoulder width apart. This will be your starting position. <br/><br/>
        2. Keep your back straight and your head up. As you inhale, bend only at the waist to the side as far as possible.<br/><br/>
        3. Focus on stretching your obliques to the lowest position. Hold this position for a second and then go back to the starting position as you exhale.<br/><br/>
        4. While inhaling, repeat this movement but bending to the other side. Hold the position for a second and then return back to the starting position as you exhale.<br/><br/>
        5. Repeat this movement for the desired amount of repetitions.<br/><br/>

        <h4>Tips</h4>
        1. Keep your body straight throughout the movement. Do not lean forward or backward.<br/><br/>
        2. Do not swing the dumbbell away from your thigh. <br/><br/>
        3. Do not move your hips or legs.<br/><br/>

        <h4>Muscles Targeted</h4>
        1. Oblique Muscles<br/>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="absworkout_2">

        <![CDATA[

        <!--Flat Bench Lying Leg Raise-->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>

        1. Lie Down on a flat bench with your back and extend your legs in front of you, off the end.<br/><br/>
        2. Place your hands under your glutes with your palms facing down. You can also hold on to the sides of the bench. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. Raise your legs until you make a 90-degrees angle with the floor and keep your extended legs as straight as possible.<br/><br/>
        4. Exhale as you raise your legs up. Hold this position for a second and then slowly lower down your legs as you inhale to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        5. Repeat this exercise for two to three sets of 10 reps each.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Rectus Abdominis or Abdominal Muscles<br/><br/>
        2. Internal Obliques <br/><br/>
        ]]>

    </string>

    <string name="absworkout_3">

        <![CDATA[

        <!--Hanging Knee Raise-->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>

        1. Grab a chin-up bar with your hands slightly wider than shoulder width, Keep your arms completely straight and your feet are off the ground with the pelvis rolled slightly backwards. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        2. As you exhale bend your knees and raise your legs until your thighs are parallel to the floor. Hold this position for a second.<br/><br/>
        3. While inhaling, lower down your legs slowly to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        4. Repeat this movement for the desired amount of repititions.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Tips</h2>
        * Perform this exercise slowly as it takes some time to getting used to.<br/><br/>
        * Do not try to use weights for the first time. You will have enough in your hands for balancing your body weight.<br/><b
        * Avoid swinging your torso.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Rectus Abdominis <br/><br/>
        2. Oblique Muscles <br/><br/>
        3. Adductors <br/>

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="absworkout_4">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Decline Crunch -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>

        1. Lie down on a decline bench and lock your legs at the end of the decline bench.<br/><br/>
        2. Place your hands across the chest. For more advanced technique, place your hands behind your head with the finger Tips slightly touching each other.<br/><br/>
        3. Raise your body slowly while you contract your abs.<br/><br/>
        4. While crunching up, Bring your elbows to either side of thighs.<br/><br/>
        5. Hold this position at the top, flex your abs for a second and then slowly lower down your body to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        6. Exhale as you go up and inhale as you go down.<br/><br/>
        7. Repeat this exercise for two to three sets of 10 reps each.<br/><br/>
        8. For more intensity, hold a weight plate across your chest for added resistance.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Tips</h2>
        Make sure there to keep at least an inch or two of space between your back and the bench at the bottom of the movement.<br/>

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="absworkout_5">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Leg Raises -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Lie Down on a floor with your back and extend your legs in front of you off the end.<br/><br/>
        2. Place your hands under your glutes with your palms facing down. You can also hold on to the sides of the bench. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. Raise your legs until you make a 90-degrees angle with the floor and keep your extended legs as straight as possible.<br/><br/>
        4. Exhale as you raise your legs up. Hold this position for a second and then slowly lower down your legs as you inhale to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        5. Repeat this exercise for two to three sets of 10 reps each.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Rectus Abdominis or Abdominal Muscles<br/><br/>
        2. Internal Obliques<br/>

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="bicepsworkout_6">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- EZ Bar Curl -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Stand up straight and hold an EZ curl bar on the outside slanted grip so that palms are facing outward and upward.<br/><br/>
        2. Keep your elbows close to your torso. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale Curl the weight up by keeping your upper arm stationary and curl the weights forward while contracting your biceps.<br/><br/>
        4. Continue the curl until the dumbbells are at shoulder level and your biceps are fully contracted. Hold this position at the top for a second and squeeze your biceps.<br/><br/>
        5. While inhaling, slowly lower down the bar back to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        6.  Repeat this movement for the desired amount of repetitions.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Biceps <br/><br/>
        2. Shoulders<br/><br/>
        3. Forearms <br/>
        ]]>

    </string>

    <string name="bicepsworkout_7">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Hammer Curls -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Standup with your torso upright holding a dumbbell in your each hand held at arms length. The elbows should be close to the torso.<br/><br/>
        2. Make sure the palms of your hands are facing each other. This will be your starting position. <br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale Curl the weight up by keeping your upper arm stationary and curl the weights forward while contracting your biceps.<br/><br/>
        4. Continue the curl until the dumbbells are at shoulder level and your biceps are fully contracted. Hold this position at the top for a second and squeeze your biceps.<br/><br/>
        5. While inhaling, slowly lower down the bar back to the starting position. <br/><br/>
        6. Repeat this movement for the desired amount of repetitions. <br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted </h2>
        1. Biceps <br/><br/>
        2. Brachioradialis<br/>

        ]]>
     </string>

    <string name="bicepsworkout_8">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Straight Bench Press -->
        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Lie down on a flat bench with your back and your feet on the floor. Using a medium width grip (grip that creates a 90-degrees angle between your upper arms and forearms) lift the bar from the rack with straight arms and hold it with your arms locked at the top. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        2. As you breathe in lower down the bar slowly from the starting position until it touches your mid chest. <br/><br/>
        3. After a pause of one count push the bar back up to the starting position as you breathe out until you have locked your elbows.<br/><br/>
        4. Focus on pushing the bar using your chest muscles. Lock your arms and squeeze your chest in the contracted position at the top of the motion, hold this position for a second and then start lowering down slowly again.<br/><br/>
        5. Repeat this movement for desired amount of repetitions. <br/><br/>
        6. When you are done with the exercise, place the bar back in the rack.<br/> <br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Pectoralis <br/><br/>
        2. Deltoids <br/><br/>
        3. Triceps Brachii<br/>

        ]]>
     </string>

    <string name="chestworkout_9">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Push Up -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Get into a plank position. Place your hands firmly on the ground, directly under the shoulders. Place your toes onto the floor to stabilize your lower body.<br/><br/>
        2. Brace your core (tighten your abs as if preparing yourself to take a punch), engage your glutes and flatten your back so that your entire body is neutral and straight.<br/><br/>
        3. While inhaling Begin to lower down your body by keeping your back flat and eyes focused about 3-4 feet in front of you to keep your neck neutral until your chest touches the floor slightly. <br/><br/>
        4. Do not let your but dip or stick out at any point throughout the movement. Draw shoulder blades back and down, keeping elbows tucked close to your body.<br/><br/>
        5. Keeping your core engaged, push your body back to the starting position as you exhale.<br/><br/>
        6. Repeat tis movement for the desired amount of repetitions.<br/>

        <h2>Tips</h2>
        1. Keep your head straight and neck stable throughout the movement.<br/><br/>
        2. Keep your shoulders back and stable. <br/><br/>
        3. Keep your hips and torso in a straight line thorughout the movement.<br/><br/>
        4. Do this exercise in a controlled tempo.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Pectoralis Major <br/><br/>
        2. Deltoids <br/><br/>
        3. Triceps Brachii<br/><br/>
        4. Abdominal Muscles<br/>
        ]]>

    </string>

    <string name="tricepsworkout_10">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Straight Bar Triceps Pushdown -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Attach a straight bar to a high pulley holding it with an overhand grip(palms facing down) standing at shoulder width.<br/><br/>
        2. Standing upright with the torso straight and a very small forward inclination bring you upper arms closer to the body and perpendicular to the floor. The forearms should be pointing up towards the pulley as you hold the bar. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale use your triceps muscles and bring the bar down until it touches the front of your thighs and arms are fully extended perpendicular to the floor. Make sure to keep your upper arms stationary next to your torso and only the forearms should move throughout the movement.<br/><br/>
        4. Hold this contracted position for a second. As you breathe in, bring the bar slowly up back to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        5. Repeat this movement for the desired amount of repetitions. <br/><br/>

        <h2>Tips</h2>
        1. Keep your back straight throughout the exercise.<br/><br/>
        2. Push your shoulders back and brace the abdominals and back.<br/> <br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted </h2>
        1. Triceps Brachii 
        ]]>

    </string>

    <string name="tricepsworkout_11">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Triceps Close Push Ups -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Lie on the floor with your face down and place your hand closer than the shoulder width so that your index fingers and thumbs make a triangle. Make sure you are holding your torso up at your arm\'s length.<br/><br/>
        2. As you inhale lower your chest until it slightly touches the floor.<br/><br/>
        3. Focus on using  your triceps and some of your pectoral muscles. As you breathe out press your upper body back up to the starting position and squeeze your chest.<br/><br/>
        4. Hold this contracted position for a second and repeat this movement for the desired amount of repetitions. <br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2> 
        1. Tricep Brachii <br/><br/>
        2. Pectoralis Major <br/><br/>
        3. Deltoids <br/><br/>
        ]]>
    </string>    

    <string name="chestworkout_12">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Decline Bench Press -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Lie down on a decline bench with your back and lock your legs at the end of the decline bench.<br/><br/>
        2. Using a medium width grip (grip that creates a 90-degrees angle between your upper arms and forearms) lift the bar from the rack with straight arms and hold it with your arms locked at the top. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you breathe in lower down the bar slowly from the starting position until it reaches at your chest level. <br/><br/>
        4. After a pause of one count push the bar back up to the starting position as you breathe out until you\'ve locked your elbows.<br/><br/>
        5. Focus on pushing the bar using your chest muscles. Flex your chest in the contracted position at the top of the motion, hold this position for a second and then start lowering down slowly again.<br/><br/>
        6. Repeat this movement for desired amount of repetitions.<br/><br/>
        7. When you are done with the exercise, place the bar back in the rack.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted </h2> 
        1. Pectoralis Major <br/><br/>
        2. Triceps <br/><br/>
        3. Deltoids <br/><br/>

        ]]>
    </string> 
    
    <string name="chestworkout_13">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Decline Dumbnell Bench Press -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Lock your legs at the end of a decline bench and hold a dumbbell in your each hand on the top of your thighs. Make sure the palms of your hand will be facing each other.<br/><br/>
        2. While you are laying down, move the dumbbells to the side of your chest at the shoulder width. Rotate the wrists so that the palms of your hands are facing away from you. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale push the dumbbells up using your pectoral muscles so that your arms are directly over your shoulders.<br/><br/>
        4. Focus on pushing the dumbbells using your pectoral muscles. Flex your chest in the contracted position at the top of the motion, hold this position for a second and then start lowering down slowly again as you breathe in.<br/><br/>
        5. Repeat this movement for the desired amount of repetitions. <br/><br/>

        <h2>Tips </h2>
        1. Keep your forearms perpendicular to the floor  throughout the motion. <br/><br/>
        2. Move the dumbbells in a controlled motion.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2> 
        1. Pectoralis Major <br/><br/>
        2. Anterior Deltoids <br/><br/>
        3. Triceps Brachii
        ]]>

    </string>
    
    <string name="chestworkout_14">
        <![CDATA[

        <!--Incline Bench Press -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Lie on an incline bench with your feet on the ground so that your head is near the end and eyes are below the racked bar.<br/><br/>
        2. Using a medium width grip(slightly wider than the shoulder width) lift the bar from the rack with straight arms hold it with your arms locked at the top. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you breathe in lower down the bar slowly from the starting position until it reaches at your nipple level.<br/><br/>
        4. After a pause of one count push the bar back up to the starting position as you breathe out until you\'ve locked your elbows.<br/><br/>
        5. Focus on pushing the bar using your chest muscles. Flex your chest in the contracted position at the top of the motion, hold this position for a second and then start lowering down slowly again.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Tips</h2> 
        1. Maintain the head, back, shoulders and feet positions.<br/><br/>
        2. Keep your wrist stiff and perpendicular to the floor and parallel to each other.<br/><br/>
        3. Do Not arch your back or raise your chest to meet the bar.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Pectoralis Major(Clavicular Head)<br/><br/>
        2. Anterior Deltoids<br/><br/>

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="chestworkout_15">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Incline Fly Dumbbell Bench Press -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Set an incline bench to a low incline angle(upto 15-30 degrees). Lie down on a bench with your back holding a dumbbell in your each hand.<br/><br/>
        2. Raise the dumbbells up above the chest with the palms facing forward and a slight bent at the elbows.Rotate the wrists of your hands so that palms of your hands facing you. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you inhale slowly begin to lower your arms while keeping the arms extended and rotate the wrists until the palms of your hands are facing each other.<br/><br/>
        4. As you exhale raise the dumbbells back up to the starting position by reversing the motion.

        <h2>Tips</h2> 
        1. At the end of the movement keep your arms extended with the palms facing the ceiling.<br/><br/>
        2. Make sure that the movement will happen only at the shoulder joint and at the wrist. There will be no motion at the elbow joint.,,<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2> 
        1. Upper chest(clavicular portion of the pectoralis major)<br/><br/>
        2. Deltoids<br/><br/>
        3. Triceps<br/><br/>

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="bicepsworkout_16">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Incline Dumbbell Curls-->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do</font></h2>
        1. Hold a dumbbell in your each hand held at arm\'s length and lie back on an incline bench.<br/><br/>
        2. The dumbbells should be at arm\'s length. Keep your elbows close to your torso and rotate your palms until they are facing forward. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale Curl the weight up and outward by keeping your upper arm stationary and forearms in line with the side deltoids. Continue the curl until the dumbbells are at shoulder level and to the sides of your deltoids. Hold this contracted position at the top of the movement for a second.<br/><br/>
        4. While exhaling lower down the dumbbells slowly back to the starting position.<br/><br/>
        ]]>

    </string>

    <string name="bicepsworkout_17">
        <![CDATA[

        <!--Wide Grip Standing Barbell Curls-->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Stand up straight with your torso upright and your feet shoulder width apart with your knees slightly bent and your abs draw in.<br/><br/>
        2. Hold a barbell with an underhand grip(palms facing upwards) at just outside the shoulder width position.Keep your elbows close to the torso and back straight. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale Curl the weight up by keeping your upper arm stationary and curl the weights forward while contracting your biceps.<br/><br/>
        4. Continue the curl until the bar is at shoulder level and your biceps are fully contracted.Hold this position at the top for a second and squeeze your biceps hard.<br/><br/>
        5. While inhaling, slowly lower down the bar back to the starting position.<br/><br/>

        <h2>Muscles Targeted</h2>
        1. Brachii <br/><br/>
        2. Brachials<br/><br/>
        3. Brachioradialis<br/><br/>

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="bicepsworkout_18">
        <![CDATA[

        <!-- Zottman Curl -->

        <h2><font color="red">Steps to do:</font></h2>
        1. Standup with your torso upright holding a dumbbell in each hand held at arms length. The elbows should be close to the torso.<br/><br/>
        2. Make sure the palms of your hands are facing each other. This will be your starting position.<br/><br/>
        3. As you exhale Curl the weight up keeping your upper arm stationary and rotate your wrist so that you have a supinated(palms up) grip. Continue the curl until the dumbbells are at shoulder level and your biceps are fully contracted.<br/><br/>
        4. Hold this contracted position at the top of the movement for a second.<br/><br/>
        5. While inhaling, lower down the dumbbells slowly back to the starting position using the pronated grip.<br/><br/>

        ]]>
    </string>


</resources>
